{"tossups": [{"question": "In this region, Vespasian served with the Legio II Augusta and participated in the Battle of the Medway. This province\u2019s northernmost reach came with Agricola\u2019s victory at Mons Graupius over the Caledonians. The Legio IX Hispania supposedly disappeared in this province, where Gaius Suetonius Paulus suppressed an uprising of the Iceni tribe after his victory in the Battle of Watling Street. Hadrian\u2019s Wall lies in, for ten points, what Roman province where Boudica sacked Londonimium?", "answer": "<b> Britannia</b> (accept descriptions of the island of Great<b> Britain</b>; do not accept England or other names)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "According to legend, after Claude Harmon performed this feat, Ben Hogan replied \u201cHow was your shot?\u201d On Sunday, April 10th, Shane Lowry, Davis Love III, and Louis Oosthuizen [oost-hoy-zen] all accomplished this feat, with Oosthuizen requiring a bounce off of J.B. Holmes\u2019 ball. This rare feat has occurred 27 times in competition at Augusta National, but is significantly more common on the Wednesday of Masters week, during the Par 3 contest. For ten points, name this feat in which a golfer finishes a hole with a minimum amount of work.", "answer": "making a<b> hole-in-one</b> (or an<b> ace</b>) at the Masters", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "In this battle, Lauzun\u2019s Legion was able to repulse a foraging party led by Banastre Tarleton. During this battle, the Gatinois regiment provided carpenters to break down palisades at Redoubt 9. One myth about this battle notes that the general who fired the first cannon shot ended up hitting a dinner table where his enemies were eating. This battle ended with the playing of the tune \u201cThe World Turned Upside Down\u201d while Charles O\u2019 Hara surrendered. For ten points, name this 1781 battle in which Cornwallis surrendered to George Washington.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Yorktown</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man depicted the murder of a working class family during the July Monarchy in his lithograph <em>Rue Transnonain</em>. One work by this artist shows a photographer in a hot air balloon taking pictures. Another work by this artist satirically depicts an obese Louis-Phillipe being fed humans as the title creature. This artist of<em> Nadar Elevating Photography to the Height of Art</em> and<em> Gargantuan</em> depicted a peasant family in a namesake carriage on a train. For ten points, name this 19th century French artist of <em>Third Class Carriage</em>.", "answer": "Honore<b> Daumier</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This event was investigated by John Kenlon. Kate Alterman was made to repeat her testimony about this event multiple times by Max Steuer, leading the jury to believe that she had memorized what to say during the trial of Max Blanck and Isaac Harris. The ILGWU grew substantially in the aftermath of this event, during which William Gunn Shephard wrote of seeing women jump out of windows because doors had been locked. For ten points, name this 1911 event in which a fire in the Asch building killed 146 garment workers.", "answer": "<b> Triangle Shirtwaist</b> Factory fire", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In March 2016, researchers found thousands of artifacts from this man\u2019s ship<em> Esmeralda</em> off the coast of Oman. The Zamorin believed that this man was not a royal ambassador because his gifts contained no gold or silver. He named Natal while passing through on Christmas Day. The<em> Sao Gabriel</em> was the flagship of this explorer, who visited Mombasa and Calicut. For ten points, name this explorer who, under the patronage of Henry the Navigator, became the first European to see India while sailing for Portugal.", "answer": "Vasco<b> de Gama</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The implementation of this policy was in question in<em> Evenwel v. Abbott</em>. In his decision in<em> Reynolds v.</em> <em>Sims</em>, Chief Justice Warren applied this principle, writing that \u201clegislators represent people, and not acres or trees.\u201d In 2016, the Supreme Court upheld a ruling that convicted felons and children are included in one half of this policy, even though they are ineligible to participate in the other half. The U.S. Senate does <em>not</em> abide by this policy; after each census, districts are re-drawn to allow the House to more accurately abide by it. For ten points, give this four-word phrase for the idea that political power should be equal for all voters.", "answer": "<b> One person, one vote</b> (accept<b> man</b> or<b> woman</b> for person; prompt on \u201credistricting\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "William Foy and Frederick Heinde were the first two men to be wounded in this event. This event was wrapped up quickly so that Robert Attison would not have an excuse to use state militia. Alexander Berkman and Emma Goldman plotted to assassinate the man they thought responsible for this event, in which a flotilla obstructed a barge\u2019s attempt to travel toward this event. This reaction to the harsh policies of Henry Clay Frick resulted in 12 deaths and the downfall of an ironworkers union. For ten points, name this 1892 strike and lockout at a steelworks in Pittsburgh.", "answer": "<b> Homestead</b> Strike", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This process took place annually in a two-stage system; first the question of whether it would happen that year, then the question of its target. One man helped an illiterate citizen perform this process by writing his own name on a potshard. Someone undergoing this process was guaranteed the return of their property after they endured it for ten years, though the Assembly could recall them early, as was done for Cimon and the father of Pericles. For ten points, name this process of democratically-chosen, temporary exile from Athens, a term that now refers generally to a process of shunning someone.", "answer": "<b> ostracism</b> (accept word forms, like<b> ostracize</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A 2013 picture of this man shows him with an inflated throat pouch in a \u201cshow of dominance over fellow Congressional males.\u201d A 2016 satirical article included another photoshopped picture of this man covered in blood holding a severed head. That article ostensibly quoted this man as saying \u201cDo not attempt to silence the voice of the American people,\u201d and reported that he had mailed his victim\u2019s hand to Sri Srinivasan as a warning. For ten points, name this politician who, fictionally, killed Merrick Garland in March 2016, \u201cfulfilling\u201d his threat that Republicans would not consider a Supreme Court nominee before the election, a promise he made as Senate Majority Leader.", "answer": "Mitch<b> McConnell</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "Thaddeus Stevens quipped that a holder of this position, Simon Cameron, \u201cwouldn\u2019t steal a red hot stove\u201d in defense of the corruption charge that led to his resignation in 1862. Albert Gallatin criticized one holder of this position after a disastrous series of events including the surrender of William Hull. The Confederation Congress appointed Benjamin Lincoln to this position, after which he was succeeded by Henry Knox, who held this position under George Washington. For ten points, name this Cabinet office that was broken up in 1947", "answer": "<b> Secretary of War</b> (do not accept or prompt on Secretary of Defense)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s post-World War II years are described in the nihilistic novel<em> The Decay of the Angel</em>. A novel set in this country features characters called The Minister of the Left and the Minister of the Right. Father Rodrigues\u2019 journal provides much of the action in a novel set in this country called<em> Silence</em>. The customs of this country\u2019s court life are detailed in<em> The Pillow Book</em>, as well as a novel featuring Lady Aoi. For ten points, name this country, the setting of<em> The Tale of Genji</em>.", "answer": "<b> Japan</b> BONUS:<em> The Pillow Book</em> was written by what Heian-era poet, who served Empress Teishi? ANSWER:<b> Sei</b> Shonagon (prompt on Shonagon)", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "The Panjshir valley was captured early on in this war. This war was preceded by Operation Storm-333, which replaced Hafizullah Amin with Babrak Karmal. It was prompted by the deterioration of relations with Nur Muhammed Taraki, who had seized power in the Saur Revolution. This conflict was opposed by Operation Cyclone, in which Stinger missiles were given to mujahideen warriors by CIA operatives. For ten points, name this decade-long conflict, a Soviet invasion of a Middle Eastern country.", "answer": "Soviet invasion of<b> Afghanistan</b> (or the Soviet-<b>Afghan</b> War)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Shortly before his death, an opponent of this policy was shackled naked to the back of a Land Rover during an 1100 kilometer road trip. A campaign of \u201crolling mass action\u201dagainst this policy led to the Bisho massacre, carried out by the armed forces of the Ciskei</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Bantustan. The armed group Umkhonto We Sizwe was established to fight this policy</b> <b>after the Sharpeville Massacre. This policy ended after the National Party was defeated in a 1994 election. (*) </b> Desmond Tutu and Nelson Mandela opposed, for ten points, what policy that denied black people rights in South Africa?", "answer": "<b> apartheid</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>During this event, an executioner named Ser Nuto was lynched, hung by his foot, and ripped apart by a mob. A group called the Eight took power during this event, after which</b> <b>the (+)</b> <b>Albizzi family rose to prominence. The first leader of this event was declared</b> <em><b>gonfaloniere</b></em><b> of justice and was named Michele di Lando, and this event was partly caused by popular resentment over the power held by the (*)</b> Arte della Lana. The participants in this uprising were part of the<em> popolo minuto</em> and had little power since they were not part of a guild. For ten points, name this uprising of wool carders in Florence.", "answer": "Revolt of the<b> Ciompi</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The most famous of these specific performances was supported by newcomers Billy Cox and Larry Lee. An early surviving recording of these performances took place at Merriweather Post Pavilion and, like the most famous of these events, includes the melody</b> <b>from (+)</b> <b>\u201cTaps.\u201d The last of these performances came in Hawaii a month before the</b> <b>performer\u2019s 1970 death in a London apartment. The most famous of these performances enjoys a good quality video recording due to the early (*)</b> morning light, as it came at the end of the Woodstock festival. For ten points, name these patriotic guitar performances by the leader of the Experience.", "answer": "Jimi<b> Hendrix</b> playing the<b> Star Spangled Banner</b> (or equivalents; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "<b>The Wood Green plot was a terrorist attempt to attack the London Underground using this substance. In 2013, this substance was included in letters that read \u201cMaybe I have your</b> <b>attention now even if that means someone must die\u201d and \u201cI am (+)</b> <b>KC and I approve</b> <b>this message\u201d; those letters were later traced to former actress Shannon Richardson. A platinum-iridium pellet containing this substance was shot out of an umbrella gun to assassinate (*) </b> Bulgarian dissident Georgi Markov. For ten points, name this toxin derived from the castor oil plant that was put in letters addressed to Barack Obama in April 2013.", "answer": "<b> ricin</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This author called attention to the wrongs of the Bangladesh Liberation War in his poem\u201cSeptember on Jessore Road.\u201d He claimed \u201cStrange now to think of you, gone without</b> <b>corsets and eyes\u201d in an elegy for his mother Naomi. This author of (+)</b> <b>\u201cKaddish\u201d also</b> <b>placed Federico Garcia Lorca and Walt Whitman in a \u201cSupermarket in California.\u201d He repeatedly assured Carl Solomon that \u201cI\u2019m (*) </b> with you in Rockland\u201d in a poem that was the subject of a notable 1957 obscenity trial. For ten points, name this Beat poet who lamented \u201cI saw the best minds of my generation destroyed by madness\u201d in his poem \u201cHowl.\u201d", "answer": "Irwin Allen<b> Ginsberg</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "<b>An attempt to enforce this law resulted in the building of a 2000-mile-long hedge to curb smuggling from one coast to the other called the Inland Customs Line. Archibald Rowlands attempted to repeal this law, but was prevented from doing so by Archibald (+) Wavell. This law affected people living in the Orissa state who had to purchase the namesake substance instead of collecting it themselves. The most famous (*) </b> resistance to this law led to the Second Round Table Conference with Lord Irwin and ended at a beach in Dandi. For ten points, name this unpopular law in British India that taxed a substance collected from the sea.", "answer": "British<b> salt tax</b> in India <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) ANSWER: Battle of<b> Thermopylae</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}